#大家好 我們是華農兄弟
Hi everyone! We are Huanong Brothers.
#今天去兄弟家 哦 不是 去我們家
Today we're going to our buddy's, oh, I mean, our orchard,
#看一下我們家那個臍橙熟了沒有
to have a look at our navel oranges, and see if they are ready
#走 開車去
Let's go, go by car.
#你看 這個
Look! This is,
#又大又紅的哦
big and red.
#我們摘一個來吃
Let's pick one now.
#摘一個 看 這裡有一個 這個
Pick one. Look! Here's one. This one is,
#這個最靚的這個
this one is the most beautiful.
#摘一個
Pick one.
0:01:05.780,0:01:07.020#
#哇 沒有指甲
Wa! I don't have long enough fingernails.
#你看 這個水份很足哦 這個水份
Look! It's filled with juice, the juice.
#哇 好甜
Wa! Sweet!
#嗯
Yum!
#這個可以 坐下來吃
This one is good. Let me sit down and enjoy it.
#大部份都黃啦 那有些還有一點青
Most are already golden yellow. Some are still green over there.
#這個青的也很好吃哦
The green ones are also very tasty.
#酸酸甜甜的
It's sweet and sour.
#這個黃一點的就是很甜的
The golden yellow ones are very sweet.
#現在
Now,
#樹頂上的 幾乎都熟啦
those at the top of the trees, are almost all ready.
#11月17號
By 17th November,
#那時候就全部 全部都熟啦
by that time, all, all will be ready.
#那時候就是全部 整個樹都是黃的
And then all, the whole tree will turn golden yellow.
#我已經吃了兩三個了
I've already eaten a couple of them,
#個個都是半斤以上的
each weighs more than half a pound.
#我們摘一點回去吧
Let's pick some home.
#來都來啦
We're already here anyway.
#哇 你看 這個
Wa! Look! This is,
#長那麼大哦
is that large!
#誒 怎麼擰兩下就把它擰下來啦
Eh? Why does it fall onto my hand? I didn't twist it hard.
#太脆弱啦
It's too fragile.
#沒辦法
Not my fault.
#爆啦 你看 這裡都
It's cracked open. Look! Here...
#哎喲
Ayo!
#哇 長太大啦
Wa! It's just too large!
#嗯 很甜哦
Um! It's really sweet.
#啊 這個給你吃
Ah! This is for you.
#嗯
Um!
#這皮好薄
The peel is thin.
#看這個果肉
Look at the pulp!
#水份很足的
It's very juicy.
#好 摘一點回去 給家人吃
Alright! Let's pick some for our families.
#來都(有)[SIC]來啦 不能空手回去啊
We're already here. We can't leave empty-handed.
#兄弟家離我家有點遠
My buddy's orchard is a bit far from us.
#幾十公里呀 將近100公里
It's dozens of kilometres, also a hundred.
#你看 這個
Look! This is,
#很靚的哦
beautiful!
#這個
It,
#皮膚好滑呀
has a smooth skin.
#棵樹全部摘掉
I'll clear this tree,
#一個都不留
of every single orange.
#我都帶了幾個牛皮袋過來
I've brought several bags with me.
#我就不信
There's no reason,
#裝不滿
for not filling them up.
#你看 這種
Look! These are,
#不是很黃的哦
still a bit green.
#放幾天的話 它就很黃啦
But they'll become golden yellow in a few days.
#這種
They,
#這個 要放個四五天左右
they still need four to five days,
#它就慢慢的變黃
to become golden yellow gradually.
#而且它的 裡面的那個
And its, you know, I mean,
#那個 那個糖啊
you know, the sugar level,
#它就越來越甜 越來越甜
it will become sweeter, sweeter and sweeter.
#現在 有點青的話就有點酸酸甜甜的口感
Now, it's still a bit green. So it's like, sweet and sour.
#稍微放久一點它 甜一點
I will be sweeter after a couple of days.
#你看
Look!
#小胖子
A chubby.
#將近一斤啊 這個
It's almost a pound.
#長那[麼][SIC]大幹嘛
Why are you that huge?
#把它放回 帶回家裡面去吃 這個
Let me place it, I mean take it back home, chubby.
#我已經吃了三四個啦 吃不下啦
I've already eaten three or four, I can't take any more now.
#這兩個
These two.
#你看 這個小的
Look! This small one,
#這個小的很好吃的哦
this small one is very tasty.
#哎呀
Aya!
#搞得我一臉都是
The juice spills all over my face.
#嗯
Um!
#這種小果很甜的
These small oranges are really sweet.
#你看 現在都還有一點青
Look! It's still a bit green,
#都那麼甜
but it's still very sweet.
#我們把整梱樹全部摘光
We'll pick every single orange from this tree,
#不管大小
every, big or small.
#都把它摘完
All will be ours.
#我要準備回去啦
Let's get ready to go back,
#就摘了那麼一點點
with just a little bit here.
#等下這袋我倒回來拿
I'll come back for the remaining bag.
#我去抓 抓一隻鴨來
I'm going to catch, catch a duck.
#差一點點 摸都摸到了沒抓住
I could almost catch it. I could touch it. But it ran away.
#這鴨子抓不到的 太不好抓啦
I can't catch the ducks. It's really hard.
#它一下池塘我們抓不到
I've no chance once they get into the pond.
#下次來
I'll be back.
#豬耳朵
Pig ear.
#哎呀
Aya!